<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[drexel-teaching]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>drexel-teaching</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:18:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:18:01 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Syllabus]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>Instructor Details

<br>Name: Darren Woodland, Jr.
<br>Email: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:dkw34@drexel.edu" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="mailto:dkw34@drexel.edu" target="_blank">dkw34@drexel.edu</a>
<br>Office Hours: By appointment through email or <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://outlook.office.com/bookwithme/user/8a28cf456da9442e97dda421b09a3af0@drexel.edu/meetingtype/MWYxQdbZA0mCye-WJGVcQw2?anonymous&amp;ep=mCardFromTile" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://outlook.office.com/bookwithme/user/8a28cf456da9442e97dda421b09a3af0@drexel.edu/meetingtype/MWYxQdbZA0mCye-WJGVcQw2?anonymous&amp;ep=mCardFromTile" target="_blank">booking</a>.

<br><br>Classroom Info

<br>Location: URBN 248
<br>Students will use Drexel Learn and their @drexel.edu emails for all class communication.

<br><br>This course introduces students to procedural real-time game systems and technical art production. Students will explore Unity-based workflows, gaining proficiency in shaders, particle systems, modeling, and visual effects. The course emphasizes real-time systems and modular design techniques.<br><br>Key Capabilities

<br>Procedural and modular modeling
<br>Shader and material development
<br>Particle and image effects
<br>Lighting, camera techniques, and post-processing

<br><br>By the end of the course, students will demonstrate skills in:<br>
<br>🤖 Procedural modeling
<br>💡 Scene lighting and camera effects
<br>✨ VFX creation
<br>🖌️ Shader and material development
<br>🔄 Technical workflows for real-time game art
<br><br><br><br>Useful Links

<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://unity3d.com/get-unity/download/archive" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://unity3d.com/get-unity/download/archive" target="_blank">Unity 2022.3.9LTS Download</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.blender.org/download/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.blender.org/download/" target="_blank">Blender 4.3 Download</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://code.visualstudio.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank">Visual Studio Code</a> or your favorite IDE (must support C# + Python)

<br><br>Useful Links

<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://unity3d.com/get-unity/download/archive" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://unity3d.com/get-unity/download/archive" target="_blank">Unity 2022.3.9LTS Download</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://learn.drexel.edu/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://learn.drexel.edu/" target="_blank">Drexel Learn</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://dl.acm.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://dl.acm.org/" target="_blank">ACM Digital Library</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.gdcvault.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.gdcvault.com/" target="_blank">GDC Vault</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://freelibrary.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://freelibrary.org/" target="_blank">LinkedIn Learning via Free Library of Philadelphia</a>

<br><br><br><br>Weeks 1-3 Highlights

<br>Fundamentals of procedural modeling
<br>Modular workflows
<br>Lighting systems focusing on geometry and light interplay

<br>Assignment 1: Create a modular game asset and integrate lighting systems.<br>
Due: Week 3<br><br>Weeks 4-5 Highlights

<br>Custom shader creation using code and visual scripting
<br>Application of shaders to procedural assets for real-time interactivity

<br>Assignment 2: Develop shaders for the asset created in Assignment 1.<br>
Due: Week 5<br><br>Weeks 6-7 Highlights

<br>Particle systems using visual scripting and component-based systems
<br>Creating interactive effects tied to game mechanics

<br>Assignment 3: Add particle and dynamic visual effects to the modular asset.<br>
Due: Week 7<br><br>Week 8 Highlights

<br>Camera manipulation techniques
<br>Post-processing pipelines for polish and visual enhancement

<br>Assignment 4: Implement camera effects and post-processing for the asset.<br>
Due: Week 8<br><br>Weeks 8-10 Focus Combine and refine work from Modules 1-4 into a polished scene or artifact.<br>Final Deliverables:<br>
<br>🎯 Cohesive scene incorporating procedural assets, shaders, VFX, lighting, and post-processing.
<br><br><br><br><br><br>Grading Breakdown

<br>35% Assignments: Bi-weekly assignments focusing on module topics.
<br>25% Final Project: Integration of course concepts into a cohesive artifact.
<br>25% Participation and Professionalism: Engagement, attendance, and critique contributions.
<br>15% Weekly Quizzes: Short assessments via Drexel Learn to reinforce key concepts.

<br><br><br><br>Classroom Activities
In order to foster a more optimal learning environment and ensure respect for all participants, the following policy is in effect during lectures, live-coding, and both guest and student presentations:<br>
- No personal electronic devices: Cell phones, tablets, laptops, and other devices must be turned off and put away unless explicitly permitted for note-taking or learning activity use.<br>
- No non-course-related activities: Gaming, video watching, social media use, or any other non-course-related activities are strictly prohibited.<br>
- Acceptable learning activities: Note-taking (electronic or handwritten) and productive doodling/drawing related to course content are permitted and encouraged.<br>
- Lab sessions: During hands-on lab portions, device use is allowed for course-related work, peer discussions, and instructor engagement.
<br>Affects Participation + Professionalism
Violations of this policy will impact the Participation and Professionalism grade. Multiple offenses may result in a zero (0) for this component of the course grade, without exception.
<br><br>Cheating and Plagiarism Definitions
Cheating or plagiarism, as defined for this course, are governed by the Drexel University Academic Integrity Policy.<br>
Both are strictly forbidden. DO NOT DO IT!<br>
All instances will be investigated and reported as outlined by Drexel University policy.<br>
They will also result in: at minimum failing the assignment and an automatic decrease&nbsp;of one letter grade for your final grade and may result in your failing the course.
<br><br>Submission Rules

<br>Submit all work via Drexel Learn (unless other wise specified).
<br>Follow assignment submission guidelines outlined in briefs
<br>Use proper file naming conventions (e.g., abc123_a1_lighting_final.mp4).

<br><br>Late Assignmnets
Assignments must be turned in on time!<br>
Lateness will automatically result in at&nbsp;minimum the loss of one letter grade.<br>
Late work incurs a 10% penalty per day.
<br><br>Attendance Requirements

<br>Attendance is mandatory. 
<br>Students are allowed one unexcused absence.
<br>Missing more than one class (unexcused) reduces your grade.
<br>Each late arrival to class will result in 50% attendance for the day.

<br>Excused Abcense
Note that an excused absence is defined as one that is the result of a condition or&nbsp;circumstance beyond the student's control, such as illness, a family crisis or&nbsp;emergency, or some other serious and important personal circumstance.
<br>Three or more absences results in course failure.<br><br>AI Use Policy
Artificial intelligence (AI) tools, such as large language models (e.g., ChatGPT or Claude), may be used in this course under specific guidelines, outlined below.
<br>Approved AI Uses

<br>AI tools are permitted for developing assets for assignments and projects, such as generating images or code snippets.
<br>Students may use AI to help better contextualize and understand code, programming concepts, and course structures. This includes using AI for code review, breakdowns, and topic summaries.
<br>All written materials, explanations, and analyses submitted for assignments should be the original work of the student. AI should not be used to generate these portions of your submissions.

<br>Use and Citation
The use of AI tools is not mandatory. Students may opt out of using AI assistants entirely if they prefer to complete all work without AI assistance.<br>
When AI tools are used, students must clearly indicate which portions of their work were created with AI assistance and which tools were used.
<br>Use and Understanding
Regardless of AI usage, students are responsible for understanding and being able to explain all aspects of their submitted work.
<br><br>Course Changes to the Course
It is very important that each student has read and understood all the materials,&nbsp;assignments, and due dates on the syllabus. It is the prerogative of the instructor to change the course during the term at their discretion in the interest of&nbsp;responding to individual class needs. Changes will be communicated to students via Drexel Learn and/or email
<br><br><br>This course, including all meetings, assignments, and activities, operates under Drexel University’s policies. All students are expected to read and fully understand these policies as they apply to the coursework and conduct within this class.<br><br>Plagiarism and Cheating Policy

<br>Plagiarism or cheating will result in a failing grade for the assignment and potential course failure and further academic discipline.

<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>Instructor Notes: Some smaller incremental updates or changes to the syllabus may not result in a notification via Drexel Learn or email.]]></description><link>gmap-395\gmap-395-syllabus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">GMAP 395/GMAP 395 - Syllabus.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:16:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to GMAP 395!]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>About the Course
GMAP 395, Advanced Game Art and Production, is an undergraduate-level course focusing on concepts and techniques related to technical art for games. 
Dive into real-time systems and game engine workflows with topics like:

<br>Shaders: Mastering visual effects and materials.
<br>Procedural Modeling: Automating asset creation.
<br>Lighting Systems: Enhancing mood and realism.
<br>Camera Effects: Dynamic cameras and post-processing.

Whether you're aiming to focus on creating visually stunning worlds or procedural game systems, this course equips you with the tools to succeed.
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
<br>Instructor: Darren Woodland, Jr.  
<br>Office Hours (by appointment): <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://outlook.office.com/bookwithme/user/8a28cf456da9442e97dda421b09a3af0@drexel.edu/meetingtype/MWYxQdbZA0mCye-WJGVcQw2?anonymous&amp;ep=mCardFromTile" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://outlook.office.com/bookwithme/user/8a28cf456da9442e97dda421b09a3af0@drexel.edu/meetingtype/MWYxQdbZA0mCye-WJGVcQw2?anonymous&amp;ep=mCardFromTile" target="_blank">Microsoft Bookings</a> or email.
<br><br><br>For questions or concerns, feel free to reach out:  <br>
<br>Email: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:dkw34@drexel.edu" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="mailto:dkw34@drexel.edu" target="_blank">dkw34@drexel.edu</a>
<br>Discord: tromboctopus
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Overview of real-time systems
<br>Introduction to game engines: Unity and Unreal Engine
<br><br>
<br>Creating custom shaders
<br>Understanding lighting interactions
<br>Case study: Stylized vs. photorealistic materials
<br><br>
<br>Introduction to procedural modeling
<br>Using Houdini and other tools for asset generation
<br>Optimizing workflows for game engines
<br><br>
<br>Real-time lighting techniques
<br>Procedural sound design and implementation
<br>Case study: Integrating sound and light for immersive environments
<br><br>
<br>A cohesive real-time scene incorporating procedural assets, shaders, VFX, lighting, and post-processing.
<br><br><br>Recommended Software

<br>Unity: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://unity.com/download" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://unity.com/download" target="_blank">Download Link</a>
<br>Blender: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.blender.org/download/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.blender.org/download/" target="_blank">Download Link</a>
<br>Visual Studio Code: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://code.visualstudio.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank">Download Link</a>

<br><br><br>"Learn to merge art with technology in innovative ways."
By the end of this course, you'll:

<br>Build visually compelling and efficient game environments.
<br>Understand the interplay of art and programming.
<br>Gain a portfolio-ready project demonstrating your technical art skills.

<br><br>]]></description><link>gmap-395\gmap-395-welcome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">GMAP 395/GMAP 395 - Welcome.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:14:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>